A Guide to the Stacy C. and Geraldine Sherwood Collection, 1903 - 2013
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Stacy C. and Geraldine Sherwood Collection, 1903 - 2013
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 07-20
approx. 10 linear ft.; 15 boxes, 4 map drawers
This collection contains correspondence, clippings, legal documents, blueprints, plats, photographs and realia from the personal and professional lives of Stacy and Geraldine Sherwood. The materials date from 1903 to 2013.
Geraldine Estep Sherwood, Stacy Charles Sherwood
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Sherwood family in 2013.
Historical and Biographical Information
Stacy Charles Sherwood was born on Main Street in what is now the City of Fairfax on September 17, 1922. He was the youngest of four children born to Albert Reuben and Annie Belle Myers Sherwood. He graduated from Fairfax High School in 1940 and served in the Army Air Forces during World War II. At the age of 27, he married Geraldine Frances Estep. He attended Strayer Business College and Georgetown University, and began his banking career in 1950.
Sherwood started as a teller with The National Bank of Fairfax and gradually rose to the position of Senior Vice President. He retired in the early 1980s.
In the course of his banking career, Sherwood also became involved in local politics. In 1956, he was elected to fill his father’s newly vacated seat on the Fairfax Town Council. When The City of Fairfax was incorporated in 1961, Stacy continued to serve until 1964. During this time, he played a key role in securing the land donated to the University of Virginia for the establishment of George Mason College, which grew into George Mason University.
Upon losing his bid for re-election to the City Council in 1964, Sherwood took a seat Board of Zoning Appeals and served in this capacity for over twenty years. A lifelong resident of the City of Fairfax, Stacy Charles Sherwood died in 2002 at age 79.
Geraldine "Gerry" Frances Estep Sherwood committed herself to a life of music at an early age. Declaring that nothing less than a "real" piano would do, she received the gift of a child’s baby grand piano at age six.
Born in Harrisonburg, Virginia on February 18, 1927 to Hubert L. and Elton Steam Estep, Gerry attended Madison College in Harrisonburg, Virginia, where she graduated in 1947 with a B.S. in Music Education and a concentration in Voice. She was a member of Kappa Delta Pi (International Honor Society in Education), Alpha Sigma Alpha social sorority and the glee club. She attended The Julliard School of Music in 1948. Upon graduation, took a job at Fairfax High School, where she spent seven years developing a choral music program. During her time at Fairfax High School, she met Stacy C. Sherwood, whom she married in 1950.
As a young housewife, Gerry turned her attention to developing the cultural life of Fairfax. In addition to giving private voice and piano lessons, she worked with the choir at the Fairfax United Methodist Church and was a founding member of the Arts Council of Fairfax County. She was involved with Fairfax Community Concerts from 1970 to 2007, served on the Board of the Fairfax Symphony Orchestra, and held various positions with the Women’s Association of the Symphony. She also spent fifty years working with The Fairfax Music Guild and The Fairfax Choral Society.
In her later years, Mrs. Sherwood gave many gifts to the City of Fairfax. The crown jewel is the Stacy C. Sherwood Community Center. Named to honor her husband’s lifetime of service to The City of Fairfax, this 14,000 square foot facility opened in 2011, offering a wide range of arts related activities and programs. The center received the Best New Facility award from the Virginia Recreation and Parks Society in 2012. Geraldine Sherwood died on August 5, 2013.
Scope and Content
Series 1: Papers, 1903-2011
Subseries 1.1: Stacy Charles Sherwood, 1911-2002
This series contains papers and photographs from the personal and professional life of Stacy C. Sherwood. Of particular interest is the election memorabilia from the time period when Sherwood served on the Fairfax City Council.
Subseries 1.2: Geraldine Estep Sherwood, 1927-2011
This series contains papers, photos and clippings from Geraldine "Gerry" Sherwood. These items highlight her career as a Fairfax High School music teacher at, along with her involvement in several local music-related organizations.
Subseries 1.3: Albert Reuben Sherwood, 1903-1962
This series contains papers, photographs, building plans and log books from Stacy Sherwood's father, Albert. A well known local builder and real estate developer, Albert planned and supervised many commercial and private projects in Washington, DC and northern Virginia.
Subseries 1.4: Myers Family Postcards, 1907-1949
This series contains correspondence in the form of postcards between members of the Sherwood and Myers families. Stacy Sherwood's mother, Annie Belle Myers moved to Tyson's Corner from Boonesboro, Maryland around the turn of the century.
Subseries 1.5: Fairfax Music Guild, 1955-1976
This series contains yearbooks, scrapbooks and administrative files from The Fairfax Music Guild.
Series 2: Realia, 1936-2013
This series contains memorabilia and artifacts from several prominent businesses located throughout the City of Fairfax and Fairfax County.
Series 3: Oversize, 1912-1962
This series contains maps, plats and blueprints, most of which Stacy Sherwood inherited from his father, Albert. Included are detailed plans and drawings for local commercial and residential building projects. The only known set of plans for Fairfax High School is contained here.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Sherwood, Stacy Charles; Sherwood, Geraldine Estep; Sherwood, Albert Reuben; Fairfax Music Guild; Fairfax Choral Society; City of Fairfax, Virginia; County of Fairfax, Virginia; Fairfax City Council; Fairfax Hospital; Fairfax United Methodist Church; National Bank of Fairfax; Fairfax High School; Fairfax County Symphony Orchestra
Container List
- Series 1: Papers, 1903-2011
  - Subseries 1.1: Stacy Charles Sherwood, 1911-2002
    - Accounts ledger, personal, 1969-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Board of Zoning Appeals case, Old Oliver House, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Country Club of Fairfax, 1974-2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, World War II, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Fairfax County Guidebook, Index of Attorneys, Historic Garden Week booklet, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Fairfax County Public Schools Centennial Committee, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - City of Fairfax Charter Study Commission, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Fairfax City Council, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Fairfax Town Council and staff, group photograph, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Fairfax elections ephemera, 1956-1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Fairfax Hospital, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Fairfax Lions Club, 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Fairfax planning and properties, 1952-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Town and City of Fairfax financial reports, 1949-1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Town of Fairfax annual reports, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Fairfax United Methodist Church, 1936-1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Fairfax United Methodist Church membership directories, 1971-1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Funeral of Stacy Sherwood, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - McCoy farm, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Mainland office building, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Memorial programs: James J. Corbalis, Nan Sherwood, Ruth Sherwood Corbalis, 1998-2006 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - National Bank of Fairfax (1 of 3), 1930-1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - National Bank of Fairfax (2 of 3), 1957-1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - National Bank of Fairfax (3 of 3), 1951-1996 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1960-1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Postcards, 1911-1931 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Albert R. and Annie Sherwood estate, 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Personal items, 1927-1966 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Real estate and financial records, 1948-1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Receipts and ephemera from local businesses, 1948-1958 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Remembrances of local history, 1934-2002 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 1.2: Geraldine Estep Sherwood, 1927-2011
    - Academic records, 1927-1955 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Calendar, notes from notebook, 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Calendars, 1949, 1985, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Calendar, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Calendars, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Calendars, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Calendars, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Christmas tags and notes, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Community Concert Association programs, 1970-1981 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Concert and recital programs, 1951-1987 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with Rachel Weldon, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Esso World War II map, 1940s (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Gifts to Eastern Mennonite University and Shenandoah University, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Fairfax County Choral Society, 1963-1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Fairfax County Symphony Orchestra (1 of 2), 1972-1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Fairfax County Symphony Orchestra (2 of 2), 1972-1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Fairfax County Symphony Orchestra Cookbook, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Fairfax High School, 1947-1953 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Fairfax High School items from unfinished scrapbook, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Fairfax High School concert programs, 1953-1960 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Fairfax High School items from blue scrapbook, 1950-1953 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Fairfax High School reunions for classes of 1941 and 1953, 2001-2003 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Madison College, 1945-1968 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - National Federation of Music Clubs, 1971-1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Photographs and newspaper clippings, 1940s-1996 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Programs - plays, worship services, concerts, 1942-1951 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Stacy C. Sherwood Community Center, 2008-2011 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - State song of Virginia, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 1.3: Albert Reuben Sherwood, 1903-1962
    - Pocket ledger and calendar, circa 1907 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Ledger, 1910-1919 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Loose papers removed from ledger, 1920-1928 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Ledgers - land and house appraisals, 1946-1954 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Ledgers - appraisals and personal, 1949-1962 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Murphy and Ames - Our Book of Modern Homes, circa 1927 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Payroll - weekly time books, 1924-1941 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Properties and financial, 1947-1952 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - The Radford Book of American Homes, 1903 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 1.4: Myers Family Postcards, 1907-1949
    - Myers Family Postcards, 1907-1949 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 1.5: Fairfax Music Guild, 1955-1976
    - Yearbooks, 1955-1982 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook, 1982-1986 (Box 13)
    - Scrapbook, 1986-1988 (Box 13)
    - Scrapbook, 1988-1990 (Box 13)
    - Scrapbook, 1990-1992 (Box 13)
    - Administrative Files: Budget, 1967-1977 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Administrative Files: By-Laws (National), Undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Administrative Files: Collect, Undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Administrative Files: Constitution and By-Laws, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Administrative Files: Correspondence, 1961-1975 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Administrative Files: Crusade for Strings, 1965-1977 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Administrative Files: Delegates' Reports, 1966-1975 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Administrative Files: District Meetings, 1962-1976 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Administrative Files: District Reports, 1962-1975 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Administrative Files: Extension and Orientation, 1967-1975 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Administrative Files: Junior Division, 1962-1970 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Administrative Files: Meeting Minutes (1 of 2), 1955-1961 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Administrative Files: Meeting Minutes (2 of 2), 1962-1967 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Administrative Files: Membership Applications, 1963-1971 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Administrative Files: Memorial Fund, 1967-1976 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Administrative Files: National Music Week, 1961-1967 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Administrative Files: National Business, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Administrative Files: Newsletter, 1965-1974 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Administrative Files: Music Camps, 1963-1966 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Administrative Files: Parade of American Music, 1964-1967 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Administrative Files: Past Presidents' Assembly, Undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Administrative Files: President's Handbook and other Aids, 1962-1970 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Administrative Files: Program Material, 1958-1969 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Administrative Files: Rating Sheets and Club Activities Reports, 1961-1977 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Administrative Files: Resignation Letters, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Administrative Files: Scholarship (Guild), 1964-1970 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Administrative Files: Scholarships, 1963-1971 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Administrative Files: State Conventions, 1963-1971 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Administrative Files: State Reports, 1961-1976 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Administrative Files: Suggestions, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1956-1991 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1961-1973 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Series 2: Realia, 1936-2013
  - Advertising pencils, local businesses, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Calendar, shoehorn, Quality Auto Body, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Ice scraper, National Bank of Fairfax, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Tote bag, Stacy C. Sherwood Community Center, 2013 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Jewelry Box - Everhart Jewelers, undated (Box 9)
  - Key Holder - National Bank of Fairfax, undated (Box 9)
  - Playing Cards - National Bank of Fairfax (2 Decks), undated (Box 9)
  - Paperweight - Fairfax Hospital Association, undated (Box 9)
  - Ballpoint Pen - George Mason Bank, undated (Box 9)
  - Golf markers - National Bank of Fairfax, undated (Box 9)
  - Dime bank - Mt. Vernon Bank and Trust, undated (Box 9)
  - Match Safe - Fairfax Motors, undated (Box 9)
  - Ashtray - National Bank of Fairfax, undated (Box 9)
  - Matchbooks - National Bank of Fairfax, undated (Box 10)
  - Matchbook - Vienna Trust Company, undated (Box 10)
  - Matchbook - Erwin Ford, undated (Box 10)
  - Matchboook - The Country Squire Restaurant, undated (Box 10)
  - Keychain - Jim McKay Chevrolet, undated (Box 10)
  - Wooden nickel - City of Fairfax, Chamber of Commerce, undated (Box 10)
  - Dog Tag - Fairfax Animal Welfare League, undated (Box 10)
  - Bowling shirt, National Bank of Fairfax bowling team, "The Credits", undated (Box 11)
- Series 3: Oversize, 1912-1962
  - Ledger, Albert Sherwood, 1912-1926 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Subdivision Plat, Fairfax Heights - Section Two, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax County Public Schools, payroll and related correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - City of Fairfax election scrapbook, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Biographical article on John C. Wood from The Washington Star Sunday Magazine, 1965 March 21 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Metal Sign, Entrance, The Everlys' Boxwood School, 10400 Stratford Ave., circa 1960 (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Fairfacts, Fairfax High School Newspaper, 1937-1950 (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - City of Fairfax election posters, 1960s (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - Newspapers, clippings, City of Fairfax election, 1962 (Drawer 2, Folder 3)
  - Drawing for Charles Vella (house) [7 sheets], 1953 January 8 (Drawer 2, Folder 4)
  - Residence for Mr. A.R. Sherwood, House No. 2 [3 sheets, 4 duplicate copies], 1942 July 20 (Drawer 2, Folder 5)
  - Commercial Zone, Fairview, 1955 June (Drawer 2, Folder 6)
  - Land purchased from heirs of Peter Magner, 1954 February 21 (Drawer 2, Folder 7)
  - Semi-Detached Houses for Wilson Farr, Esq. [6 sheets], 1941 June 28 (Drawer 2, Folder 8)
  - House at Fairfax, VA for Mr. A.R. Sherwood [4 sheets, 2 duplicate copies], 1941 November 10 (Drawer 2, Folder 9)
  - Resubdivision of Lots 1,2,3,4 and 5, Section Four, Westmore, Town of Fairfax, 1953 October 6 (Drawer 2, Folder 10)
  - A Portion of the Land of Albert R. Sherwood, Town of Fairfax [2 duplicate copies], 1955 August 26 (Drawer 2, Folder 11)
  - Property of W. Lewis and Frances S. Leigh, 1950 June 12 (Drawer 2, Folder 12)
  - Semi-Detached Houses for Wilson Farr, Cellar Floor Plan and Heating Layout, 1947 June 5 (Drawer 2, Folder 13)
  - Hot Water Heating Apparatus, Residence of Mr. A.R. Sherwood, [4 sheets], undated (Drawer 2, Folder 14)
  - Property of Albert R. Sherwood, Fairfax Heights [3 duplicate copies], 1942 April 16 (Drawer 2, Folder 15)
  - Plat of Moore and Oliver Subdivision [2 duplicate copies], undated (Drawer 2, Folder 16)
  - Unknown Commercial Building [3 sheets], undated (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - Fairfax High School [12 sheets], 1934 April (Drawer 3, Folder 2)
  - Resubdivision of Parts of the Original Lots 11 and 12 of Westmore Subdivision, Section Three, Town of Fairfax, 1942 October 31 (Drawer 3, Folder 3)
  - Plot Plan and Schedules: Garage Building and Kennel, Jermantown Road [9 sheets], 1953 August 5 (Drawer 3, Folder 4)
  - Drawings for Unknown Home (John Sherwood home?) [4 sheets], undated (Drawer 3, Folder 5)
  - Cobbdale, Providence District, Fairfax County, Virginia, 1947 May 16 (Drawer 3, Folder 6)
  - Herndon High School, Heating Plan [3 sheets], undated (Drawer 3, Folder 7)
  - Location Map, Sewage System, Town of Fairfax, with notations (2 copies), 1946 September (Drawer 3, Folder 8)
  - Proposed Storefront, Fairfax, Virginia, undated (Drawer 3, Folder 9)
  - Profile Showing Sewer Extension, Roberts Road, Singing Pines, undated (Drawer 3, Folder 10)
  - Sanitary Sewer Profile, Warwick Street, 1950 June 16 (Drawer 3, Folder 11)
  - Sanitary Sewer Plan and Profile, Sager Avenue, Maple Hill Subdivision, 1951 September 26 (Drawer 3, Folder 12)
  - Residence for Mr. H.N. Clark [7 sheets], 1926 August 21 (Drawer 3, Folder 13)
  - Drawings for unknown home, W.I. Deming, Architect, revised [9 sheets], 1927 March (Drawer 3, Folder 14)
  - Addition to Fairfax High School [10 sheets], 1938 August (Drawer 4, Folder 1)
  - Dunn-Loring School, Fairfax County, Virginia (some tears, losses) [4 sheets], 1939 January (Drawer 4, Folder 2)
  - Septic Tank and Sewage Disposal System for Pupil School, 1928 November (Drawer 4, Folder 3)
  - Land of W.M. Farr and A.R. Sherwood, Centreville, undated (Drawer 4, Folder 4)
  - Map of Fairfax, VA, Showing Sanitary Sewerage System, undated
  - Map of Town of Fairfax, Virginia, undated